[SPEAKER_02]: to many people in the area.
[SPEAKER_02]: However, we thought here at WHBL Sports, that is, that it was high time we recorded an interview with Mr. Joe Houser.
[SPEAKER_02]: Maybe there are some people in the area such as I was about a year ago who really didn't know too much about Joe because I'm a newcomer to the area.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I've been here a year and a half and I have been hearing bits and pieces of Joe Houser in baseball as time goes on.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe Houser,
[SPEAKER_02]: home run hitter of minor league baseball established a 63 home run record in the International League in 1930 to give you a basic rundown on who he is.
[SPEAKER_02]: While playing with Minneapolis in the American Association League he hit 69 home runs an all time record.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's the only man in the majors or minors to ever accomplish this kind of record and to ever have hit
[SPEAKER_02]: 60 over 60 home runs in two separate seasons.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now Joe how are you today?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm feeling fine John.
[SPEAKER_01]: I kind of like the reminiscence and get that here about my home runs of years ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're looking as bright as ever.
[SPEAKER_02]: I feel fine too.
[SPEAKER_02]: You look younger every day.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's what they all tell me.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe it's amazing that you you can appear this way and have had so many active moments back in the 30s as far back as the 30s.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, we'd like to move this thing right along.
[SPEAKER_02]: A question I've always thought that I'd like to ask a fellow like you is, how do you see baseball yesterday and today?
[SPEAKER_02]: I know that takes in an awful wide spectrum, but maybe we can get into it a little here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, John, when I played baseball back in the 20s and 30s, we played all day ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we had our living conditions.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were regular.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had our meals at the right time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And with this night ball today, twilight, and it changes the difference of living with a ball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, when I played night ball later on in my career, we did a dinner at 3.30 in the afternoon and play our ball game and probably have a breakfast at midnight.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that changes things quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: And with the night ball and twilight, the conditions are bad for the hitter insofar as seeing the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's a lot of differences of playing at six and seven o'clock at night and two o'clock in the afternoon when I played.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then of course you get into your night ball with the lights on and there's a lot of deception.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course the lights are better today than they are than they were when I played.
[SPEAKER_01]: And therefore you see less hitting today than you did 20 30 years ago when you play strictly baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well Joe I consider myself a youngster here now when we're talking about these days in the sense that are you talking about no lights at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I'm talking about day ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then, of course, like the Boers tonight are playing a twilight doubleheader.
[SPEAKER_02]: Right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, that twilight game tonight, they ain't gonna see much of that baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because you're running into that time of the day where you don't see the ball too good.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's too much deception on the speed of that ball coming up to that plate.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then the darker it gets, the worse it gets.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because sometimes they lose a ball in the sky, a fly ball, they don't even see the ball up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: It drops safe for a base hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: And those are the conditions, and that's the atmosphere you've got to look at when that pitcher turns that ball loose at you.
[SPEAKER_01]: However, today, with the lighting facilities, there's... Well, the lighting is lots better today than it was during my time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, I haven't played under these lights in...
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm out of baseball 30 years, so to speak, so...
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know really what the conditions are, but I know there's still a handicap.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's in the pitcher's favor of getting the batter out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because the pitcher looks like he's got lots more stuff at night than he has in the daytime.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe, was it more dangerous to play ball then than it is now?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we didn't seem to have no danger of playing like they got today.
[SPEAKER_01]: They got helmets on, and some of them even wore a shin guard.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't seem to have those problems them days.
[SPEAKER_01]: And today, that's the reason I say the conditions are so much different.
[SPEAKER_01]: That ball gets up on top of you, and the hitter doesn't have that protection like we had when we played day ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: So they lose a pitch every once in a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's sewn up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Don't see it at all.
[SPEAKER_02]: With all these night games.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Let's move right on to something else another legend in baseball Babe Ruth or the babe was the greatest today his record Some say is I'll use the word that's a little heavy, but I think I'll use it anyhow They say his record is being threatened by him Hank Aaron.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I can realize that and really, I think that Henry's gonna break the babes record the baby hit 714 and and I believe as of now is about 75 home runs behind and
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'm sure that if Henry can play another two years and running into the third year possibly, I'm sure that he's going to catch the babe.
[SPEAKER_01]: And of course now there's going to be something to that with Henry breaking Babe's record.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's going to be up to that about 3,000 times more than the Babe.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that's about four or five more years of playing days, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And now let's stop right here.
[SPEAKER_02]: What we're establishing or what you're establishing to me is that
[SPEAKER_02]: He may break this record, but not truly in a sense, because he has more games to his credit.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he's going to have more times at bat.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, you see where that sets in?
[SPEAKER_01]: They've got an average of about 125 base on balls a year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, Henry don't get that many base on balls.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is Henry already by the time where he could have tied
[SPEAKER_02]: The record in the same amount of correct correct same like this.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's working on overtime right now Isn't that something similar to Roger Maris's situation back a few years ago?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes Roger broke babes record getting 61 home runs.
[SPEAKER_01]: He done that in about six more ballgame so to speak, you know, so naturally they recognized the babe of having a record in the amount of games that he that they they had Established at that time for the season and of course when marriage to hit his 61 day there was six more games scheduled
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe, don't be modest with me.
[SPEAKER_02]: How can we compare you and the Babe?
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, I know he was major leaguer and you were in the minor leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you are the only man to have ever hit over 60 home runs in two separate seasons.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, well, I can't compare myself with the Babe.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Babe was an individual that... Did you know him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I played six years against him and I loved to play against him.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was an honor to be in the same ballpark with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the Babe could just hit that ball so far that it was outstanding comparing it with other long balls you've seen.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when the Babe hit one, well, that stood out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, he didn't hit them all 500, 600 feet.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the Babe, he looked good when he missed the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: People would say, well, gee, the Babe struck out twice today, but boy, he looked good swinging.
[SPEAKER_01]: And where would that ball go if he'd hit it?
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, they get that thrilled by him missing the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: He looked as good as they say.
[SPEAKER_02]: He looked good missing the ball, really.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, you and I talked about this a moment or two ago.
[SPEAKER_02]: before the interview.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he really point, was it the left field wall?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I think it was right field there in the Cubs Park.
[SPEAKER_02]: Right field, okay.
[SPEAKER_01]: Actually, there was some commotion going on in the dugout and I think they were riding the babe and I think the babe made a gesture with his fist that, come on up here and I'll give you a poke or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think that all set together like he was pointing to the
[SPEAKER_01]: to the bleachers that he was going to hit the next pitch out of the park.
[SPEAKER_01]: So thus goes the legend.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I think that's that's what really happened.
[SPEAKER_02]: But most avid sports fans, of course, would rather care to think that he pointed.
[SPEAKER_02]: Right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Correct.
[SPEAKER_02]: And there's a isn't there another part of the story that he did this for a youngster?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he was a great guy to visiting young boys and sick boys in hospitals and stuff.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the kids would say, well, babe, you hit one for me today.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, the babe hit one almost every day, every other day, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: So naturally, they'd always say, well, there's one for the kid, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, getting back now, actually, he was in the majors.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you know, the babe, you know, she started out as a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: I have a few notes here I'd like to talk about.
[SPEAKER_01]: The babe started out in 1914 as a pitcher with the Red Sox, and they pitched for four years.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he had quite some records as a pitcher, too, by the way.
[SPEAKER_01]: He won 16-6, 23-12, 24-13, 13-7.
[SPEAKER_01]: And in the meantime, he played the outfield.
[SPEAKER_01]: So actually, from 1920 on to 1935, he played regular as an outfielder.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's where he got in the groove more about hitting his home runs.
[SPEAKER_01]: And if I remember right, I think the Babe hit over 44 about eight different years in one year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, Henry Aaron's best year was last year at 44.
[SPEAKER_01]: And of course, Henry's going to catch the baby, there's no question about it, but in more games.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's for sure.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, he's going to... As you say, he's already on overtime.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_02]: So there really has never been a person to tie or equal or better his record by the same number of games I'm one of these boys from the old school.
[SPEAKER_01]: I like Henry Henry's a good friend of mine, but I still like the babe I hope his record stand.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, no one's broken yours Joe.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I tell you what these 63 and 69 home runs they're playing this night ball today
[SPEAKER_01]: You can't see the ball half the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know how anybody's going to make it, really.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, I played some night ball, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't see it neither, but I was fortunate, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: They threw the ball without swinging, John.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what happened.
[SPEAKER_02]: I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: A night game, you're saying, was a rare animal in those days.
[SPEAKER_02]: Real rare, yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is there anything else you can think of, Joe, that we could compare the 30s and maybe... Well, one thing about playing today, they got a little better equipment than what we had when we played.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had smaller gloves and we had to contend with the equipment that we had at that time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I remember I played an exhibition game up in Minneapolis three, four years ago and I had that little first baseman glove of mine up there and I threw it offside there and the fellas picked it up and said, look at that glove that fella's got there.
[SPEAKER_01]: No wonder they hit 400 when Joe played up there in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: But in the same token, with these little gloves we had, we made all the plays.
[SPEAKER_01]: And if we didn't stop the ball, we got an error and we had pretty good feeling averages.
[SPEAKER_01]: We done a good job out there with those little gloves.
[SPEAKER_01]: Chances are with the big gloves today, they may snare a ball once in a while that we may not get to, but that wouldn't happen often.
[SPEAKER_01]: Have the rules changed much?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, the rules are about the same.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, by the way, they did lower the pitching mound last year seven inches.
[SPEAKER_01]: From 17, they dropped it down to 10, and that gave the hitter a little bit more of a chance of picking up the ball faster from the grade of the pitch, the angle of the pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that made the difference, and therefore the hitting did increase a little bit the last year or two.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's
[SPEAKER_02]: All very interesting to me when I think of baseball not changing as much as some of the other sports, such as NBA basketball and hockey and a lot of the traditional games, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is it not true that baseball has changed probably the least of any?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I don't think it has changed any other than... What, do you think it needs change?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I don't think that neither.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think they should play more day ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I like to watch day baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't get a kick out of a night game at all myself.
[SPEAKER_01]: I like to watch day game.
[SPEAKER_01]: I like to
[SPEAKER_01]: Sit out there in that sun and enjoy the baseball game.
[SPEAKER_02]: Possibly easier on the fans, is it not?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, of course your hours are bad at night.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't like that lateness.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm getting to be an old man and my hours are bad.
[SPEAKER_02]: You certainly don't have any problem, Bill.
[SPEAKER_02]: This has been an extreme pleasure talking with you.
[SPEAKER_02]: One more thing maybe we can speak on before this is over with.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we'd like you to come back sometime, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I'd be glad to.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did you see that strike business this year?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you think that hurt baseball's image?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I didn't like it, and I know a lot of the players didn't like it, and of course they had a man leading that outfit, and I think they were all going with the boss, all figuring that they're going to get a break through the strike and get more money in their pension, and I know it didn't help the ballplayers any.
[SPEAKER_01]: At the time of the strike, the players were in shape, they were ready to open up the season, and I'm sure by opening the season that they were all caught short not being in shape.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they were handicapped some and I think they still are.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course the weather's been bad.
[SPEAKER_01]: They've been playing in cool weather and I know there's a lot of good hitters that are hitting way below their weight.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I know they're not happy with it but I'm sure that all these hitters that are hitting bad right now I'm sure with the weather changing getting better and more like baseball weather I think they're all going to improve in their hitting.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe Hauser this has been a pleasure for me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I really appreciate your stopping by and talking with us.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a privilege to me because I've never really
[SPEAKER_02]: talked with a person who has set the record such as yours before in the in the world of baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I don't think there's that much difference in the minor and major leagues.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not when you're speaking of records of this nature.
[SPEAKER_01]: I believe if a fellow is a good minor league hitter especially in AAA that I'm sure that he could hit in the big leagues also because you get better balls of swing at you get a good clean ball all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you've got a good umpire back there and everybody's hustling for their job.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'm sure it's up to the individual to do the job once he gets up there if he doesn't get scared by being in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm sure he could do the job also in the big leagues if he's a good minor league hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe, thanks again.
[SPEAKER_01]: Will you come back sometime?
[SPEAKER_02]: Sure, I'd be glad to, John.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very good.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ladies and gentlemen, we've been speaking with Joe Hauser, Hall of Famer, living right here in the city of Sheboygan, one of our own fine, upstanding citizens.
[SPEAKER_02]: We hope you've enjoyed the special sports interview on WHBL.
[SPEAKER_03]: This taped interview, which I have copied here, was made, we're not quite sure, I think it was in 73, either
[SPEAKER_03]: after the season or during the winter.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was obviously after the baseball strike.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was made by a young chap from the Sheboygan radio station who interviewed Joe Hauser there in the studio.
[SPEAKER_03]: Joe is very proud of this interview.
[SPEAKER_03]: He wanted me to listen to it while I was interviewing Joe himself up there in Sheboygan last Thursday.
[SPEAKER_03]: This is now Sunday, March 21st.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm back here home.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was up in Sheboygan on Thursday, March 18.
[SPEAKER_03]: I spent the day driving up there and being there and driving back to Chicago where I was on my Western interviewing tour.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had a great interview, but he had this tape, a copy of which was given to him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He wanted to play it, and we listened to it there during our afternoon session.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he wanted me to take it back with me and make a copy of it for my own use and then return it to him.
[SPEAKER_03]: And some of the things that were brought up in this taped interview by John McGowan
[SPEAKER_03]: We touched on later in our own interview, in the afternoon session, things like the uniform or the equipment changes in night baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: We got into some of those.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I think I have those perhaps in a little more detail in my own tape.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he thought this was a great tape, and I thought it was pretty good, although this young fellow didn't know too much about the baseball history.
[SPEAKER_03]: It didn't sound like he knew Joe Hauser was even in the big league.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had a pretty good career himself there for a while.
[SPEAKER_03]: I brought it back with me and I'm copying it onto this, this rest of the Stanley Kowalewski tape.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then I'll, so I'll be able to turn it to him.
[SPEAKER_04]: First of all, we got to get it back on the road here.
[SPEAKER_04]: Here we go.
[SPEAKER_04]: This is our interview with Kowalewski.
[SPEAKER_04]: We talked to him yesterday afternoon, which was Monday, May 13, 1974, at his home on West Napier Street in
[SPEAKER_04]: We were there about two hours, about two to four, and then left to go to Alabama.
[SPEAKER_04]: We got one whole tape, one 90-minute tape on both sides.
[SPEAKER_04]: Then he kept telling stories, so I stuck another tape on there.
[SPEAKER_04]: and we did about half of that for one side of that so I thought we'd finish up the other side here by talking about things which we noticed and attitudes they showed which won't appear on the tape.
[SPEAKER_04]: That was a discount distributor service truck just went by.
[SPEAKER_04]: Okay, you start it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Describe the room, or the house, in the neighborhood, why don't you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the house was a fairly good-sized house on one floor, painted white, porch around it, beautiful little lawn, and a nyard fence around the yard as a whole.
[SPEAKER_00]: It seems the entire neighborhood is infiltrated with blacks, which makes them very, very unhappy.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they've taken anything of real value out of the house, for the most part, except what's in that one room.
[SPEAKER_00]: Which I take it must include his World Series screen, since they weren't, since they didn't show them to us.
[SPEAKER_04]: I did that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, um, that one room that we were in
[SPEAKER_00]: sort of like a sunroom, was devoted to all his baseball things and his hunting things.
[SPEAKER_04]: There were two deer, one on one wall.
[SPEAKER_04]: Stuffed with the heads sticking out?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, stuffed heads of deer that he had shot.
[SPEAKER_00]: And on the floor there was a black bear skin.
[SPEAKER_00]: with the head sticking out from under the table.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't even see it at first.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the paws are falling off because they didn't have it treated after you killed it or skinned it or whatever you do to it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Put a bear's head there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay, now three walls are covered with pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the one wall
[SPEAKER_00]: that was opposite where you were sitting behind me yeah there was the um big picture of jerry gunroo's autograph big picture of ruth autograph then that huge picture kovaleski pitching and he was saying was an autograph a copy of which he gave me take with me and get uh
[SPEAKER_04]: You'd autograph that copy you gave me, you know, but you can't barely see it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, really?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: It was with a marking, a ballpoint pen that wasn't working or something.
[SPEAKER_04]: You could see the imprint on the picture, but no writing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then there were a lot of little teen pictures on that wall.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the television was backing on that wall.
[SPEAKER_00]: And on top of the television were all the balls, which I take it were for the Hall of Fame dinners in Bradenton.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because they're in a different type of case.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're on a, there's a wooden base about two and a half or three inches high with that gold plate on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It says Hall of Fame Recognition Dinner or something, Bradenton, Florida.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the date.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then up from that are these four gold arms.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like a double X, curved, the meat in the middle.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the four prongs come out and hold the ball in the glass case, the autograph ball of all the people that were there at that dinner, all the men.
[SPEAKER_00]: Whereas on the desk on my right, on the street side, those must have been the balls from Cooperstown, because those were the same ones
[SPEAKER_00]: that Haynes had in the plastic case on the flat base.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were five of one.
[SPEAKER_00]: 69, 70, 71, 72, and 73.
[SPEAKER_00]: That would be right, five.
[SPEAKER_04]: Good observer.
[SPEAKER_00]: And five of the other, four of the other, and then a couple must have been team balls because they were mounted on anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, it's one whole beat up brown ball, but I didn't see what that was.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, you couldn't tell.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was just in a case, period.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't see if it had any writing on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, and his Hall of Fame plaque.
[SPEAKER_00]: The one he got at the Hall of Fame was on that wall behind me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then a raft of other plaques that he got from various, like for the Pennsylvania Sports Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_00]: and something from Indiana for something or other.
[SPEAKER_00]: Those were all plaques of various kinds for baseball and that he had been awarded.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then on the wall behind you, it was just a lot of team pictures and group pictures.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, there's some good ones there.
[SPEAKER_04]: I wish I'd had a chance to look at them better.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a lot of those ones.
[SPEAKER_04]: How would you describe their
[SPEAKER_04]: reception of us, their attitude towards us as the afternoon progressed.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hope got warmer and warmer, especially after we had our little drink.
[SPEAKER_04]: I thought about that.
[SPEAKER_04]: What, our little drink?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, all of it, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, well she was, I think the whole thing is that they resent, they're worried in case you ask them about
[SPEAKER_00]: Something about comparing a modern player to an older player or their opinion of modern baseball and modern players, which obviously is not very good.
[SPEAKER_00]: They resent them.
[SPEAKER_00]: They don't think they work at it very hard.
[SPEAKER_00]: They, which in prima donnas is what I gather,
[SPEAKER_00]: They felt as strongly about modern baseball players as they do about the Hall of Fame selection.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Blacks.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they would never, never buy the way into the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they do think that it's a good idea.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because they just wish a lot of the old timers could get in earlier so they could enjoy it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because they say there's nothing really like it.
[SPEAKER_00]: They have a taxi stand.
[SPEAKER_00]: They take them to the airport.
[SPEAKER_00]: They fly them up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They have a beautiful room.
[SPEAKER_00]: They sign for everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's always a huge bouquet of flowers or a plant or something for the wife of the player.
[SPEAKER_00]: and then there are all the the dinners and everything and uh she said you there's just that's their holiday that's their vacation they have the trip to florida where they also pay everything but this past year they didn't have this trip to florida and she doesn't know why because they hadn't read anything about it or that and uh
[SPEAKER_00]: Unless it was the gas situation, is what they were wondering.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, a shortage of fuel when they usually have it in the middle of winter.
[SPEAKER_00]: And what happened to their other boy by his first wife?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know, because he never mentioned it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, they got, once he knew we weren't talking about modern ballplayers in comparison, so he didn't mind the tape at all.
[SPEAKER_04]: We have a feeling they didn't want to see us go.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh my goodness, no.
[SPEAKER_04]: In fact, we didn't particularly want to go, except I wanted to get over.
[SPEAKER_04]: I had a four o'clock appointment with Ollie Bema.
[SPEAKER_00]: She even kissed me goodbye.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, they got very friendly.
[SPEAKER_04]: They were friendly to begin with, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I think they were too.
[SPEAKER_04]: But they got more so.
[SPEAKER_04]: They were offering us drinks and everything else.
[SPEAKER_04]: She offered me another drink, but not him.
[SPEAKER_04]: She said, what about me?
[SPEAKER_04]: I think that's on the tape, maybe.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, because he takes his whiskey straight.
[SPEAKER_04]: I actually brought him water one time and he rejected it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Thankfully.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the coughing spell he had was because I tried to drink it straight.
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't know what it was.
[SPEAKER_04]: It was raw liquor.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did she have anything?
[SPEAKER_00]: I think she had it out in the kitchen.
[SPEAKER_00]: She didn't bring it in.
[SPEAKER_04]: How do you think she had it out there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Because she was licking her lips.
[SPEAKER_00]: She came back in and then wiped them.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I figured she'd have a little something or other out there after she did this.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the house is plain.
[SPEAKER_00]: They obviously don't have too much money, but by the same token, they're obviously very happy.
[SPEAKER_00]: She apparently worked for a while.
[SPEAKER_04]: We couldn't find that he worked at all after baseball.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And yet he must have, if he came back and was paid to manage that athletic, that amateur ball club, he must have picked up odd money here and there, I would think.
[SPEAKER_04]: I meant after that.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_04]: I didn't realize that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, you know, that's 40 years he hasn't worked.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's a long time.
[SPEAKER_04]: I know.
[SPEAKER_00]: That would be, it would only be 40 when he stopped working in his 40s.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why I think he must have done something.
[SPEAKER_04]: Maybe he sold fish.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know that about his aquarium is on the tape already, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: About his fish pond in the garage.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where he'd go out and pick up his own.
[SPEAKER_00]: But she must have worked for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: And uh...
[SPEAKER_00]: that must be how they got some of their money because I mean they're money conscious and yet they had all those uh cards from the hall of fame you know that she gave me a copy of this hall of fame plaque with his autograph on it he did she did he had a bunch of scrapbooks small ones about uh
[SPEAKER_04]: I'd say maybe 10 inches long, about 7 or 8 inches deep high, in which he had his clippings put in endwise.
[SPEAKER_04]: Trimmed neatly, newspaper column widths mounted and well preserved.
[SPEAKER_04]: He says he did this all himself.
[SPEAKER_04]: I just looked at one or two of those, which are very good.
[SPEAKER_04]: You saw a scrapbook, what was in that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, that was a new one.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the kind that, you know, modern type scrapbook where you take the picture and when you stick it, it sticks to that gum paper and then you can't move it for a lot more money.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the plastic sheet goes over.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was mostly of their last trip to Cooperstown.
[SPEAKER_00]: or their trips to Cooperstown when he was inducted, because he was inducted the same year Musial was inducted.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were a pretty sharp couple when they were all dressed up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, they didn't look the same at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: And awesome.
[SPEAKER_04]: The General Nutrition Center is just right by.
[SPEAKER_00]: Also in that scrapbook at the very beginning were four Christmas cards from the White House from President and Mrs. Nixon.
[SPEAKER_00]: With each one, three of them, had pictures of the White House on them in various things.
[SPEAKER_00]: One was a winter scene.
[SPEAKER_00]: The White House, one was red with a white embossed imprint of the White House in the center, and the other was in green with a picture of the White House.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was from President and Mrs. Nixon.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were right at the beginning of scrapping.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you see many loose, glossy, or full-sized original prints of anything in your book?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they had, they were, of course they were attached on this sticky paper, like I said.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, I think they must have been reproductions because although they were old pictures, they were, they were new prints.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, you could tell they were new prints.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were eight and a half by eleven.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why I wish you had had your camera there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because he had one of, did he play with the A's?
[SPEAKER_04]: It's that one year, 1912.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he had one picture of all the A's lined up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had a picture of himself.
[SPEAKER_04]: In fact, he joined them the year after Patty Livingston left them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Harris or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think one of him could have been left in Grove or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, there were quite a few pictures like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, whether he got those at the Hall of Fame or not, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: but they were new prints of pictures.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, you mean of players?
[SPEAKER_04]: Of old players.
[SPEAKER_04]: Today?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, these were prints of old prints.
[SPEAKER_00]: These were pictures of old ballplayers, but they were new prints of these old pictures.
[SPEAKER_04]: But the old ballplayers were young?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, while they were young.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, I mean, obviously they've been taken by somebody or copied or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: the kind that you'll get you know like they give you a picture of the Marietta football team every time Lou Yeager sends over when he sends a copy that type of print is what it was I mean you knew it was a new print because it wasn't this and it was also in that scrapbook and everything they have is done
[SPEAKER_00]: numerically or chronologically, and I don't think those old things would be out of date if they hadn't just gotten them recently.
[SPEAKER_04]: I got the idea he was a pretty casual, easygoing, lazy guy.
[SPEAKER_04]: He'd sit around chewing tobacco, fishing.
[SPEAKER_04]: But the scrapbooks were done with great care.
[SPEAKER_04]: And he was proud of them.
[SPEAKER_04]: He did a real good job.
[SPEAKER_04]: I was a little surprised to hear he had done them.
[SPEAKER_04]: I asked if his wife had maybe.
[SPEAKER_04]: No, he said he'd done them.
[SPEAKER_04]: I thought he'd be a little too casual for that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he'd be quite meticulous.
[SPEAKER_04]: He's meticulous in his pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you could tell by the way that yard was kept.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because it was neat.
[SPEAKER_04]: Maybe he's meticulous in a very casual way.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I just don't think money means anything to him.
[SPEAKER_04]: How about the chewing tobacco?
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't mean that he did.
[SPEAKER_04]: Cuspidor, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, his little Cuspidor.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now his Cuspidor was a coffee can.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, a big one.
[SPEAKER_04]: A big coffee can.
[SPEAKER_04]: Because he wasn't that good in the shot.
[SPEAKER_00]: And apparently he's chewed since...
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, as he said, he started the coal mines to keep the coal dust out of us.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, he told us that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's just always done it.
[SPEAKER_04]: But she kept wanting to get that cuspidor out of sight, and he kept bringing it back.
[SPEAKER_04]: He had it right to the side of him, just like Patty Livingston did.
[SPEAKER_04]: He had his cuspidor, he moved it around with him.
[SPEAKER_04]: He may have had a couple of strategic points, depending on which chair he was in.
[SPEAKER_00]: But obviously where they live causes them a lot of worry because the house is all locked up.
[SPEAKER_00]: She spent all the time looking out the window watching our car.
[SPEAKER_00]: See that nobody got near it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, she could see our car from where she was sitting.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_04]: I didn't notice that.
[SPEAKER_04]: There's a little thing that's very interesting you threw in.
[SPEAKER_04]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_04]: Throw in some more things like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'm trying to think what else she told me that wouldn't be on the tank.
[SPEAKER_00]: I told you something last night and you said it wasn't on the tape.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, what was it?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you want to tell it again?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's what I apparently think what it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a real nice decoupage plaque on the third wall where there were pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: Their daughter-in-law's
[SPEAKER_00]: niece's girlfriend did or something she's in high school got a little it must have been about uh 18 inches long maybe 20 about nine or eight or nine inches wide and it had old sports headlines and a picture of a 17 1876 baseball player on it and uh other little baseball things all cut out and made into a
[SPEAKER_00]: a decoupage plaque.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was very colorful and very pretty and very well done.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the knees herself had done that pencil drawing of them from an old photograph that was hanging up on that wall behind you.
[SPEAKER_04]: Very good.
[SPEAKER_04]: Keep going.
[SPEAKER_04]: And, uh, let me see what else.
[SPEAKER_04]: How was the house furnished?
[SPEAKER_00]: 1920 ish.
[SPEAKER_00]: With the old oriental type rucks in the center.
[SPEAKER_04]: The wooden floors around it.
[SPEAKER_04]: We sat in a couple of nice easy chairs.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had a couch in that television room, baseball room.
[SPEAKER_00]: And uh, they do have a phone apparently.
[SPEAKER_04]: Your bathroom was all clean and tidy.
[SPEAKER_04]: You didn't go there, though.
No.
[SPEAKER_04]: I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you have the claw legs on the bathtub?
[SPEAKER_04]: I didn't notice that.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, funny.
[SPEAKER_04]: I should have.
[SPEAKER_04]: We should have gone.
[SPEAKER_00]: And pictures of Jesus and Mary all over the place.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they didn't have as many as Oli, as Oli, Bima did.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, uh, they had quite a few of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a couple in the living room.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't have any in the baseball room.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a small statue of Mary in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And a plant.
[SPEAKER_00]: And one by the baseballs on top of the television.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think they had a little statue of Jesus.
[SPEAKER_04]: That was El Donfrio of Toledo truck with a lot of sacks of cement going on by.
[SPEAKER_04]: We are at this point traveling between the exits 9 and 10 I think heading to our Angola about 225 central time.
[SPEAKER_04]: 40 miles from the high line we just passed the sign.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's about 325
[SPEAKER_04]: Eastern time.
[SPEAKER_04]: Angola I see about 26 miles away.
[SPEAKER_04]: On this afternoon.
[SPEAKER_04]: Okay, I remember.
[SPEAKER_04]: Describing Mrs. Kowalewski.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'd say she was about, what, 5'2"?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Short.
[SPEAKER_04]: Spare.
[SPEAKER_00]: Spare.
[SPEAKER_04]: And, uh, sort of, uh... Youngish face, but kind of aligned when you got close to her.
[SPEAKER_04]: How old would you say she was?
[SPEAKER_04]: Seventy-five?
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_04]: She'd be that old.
[SPEAKER_00]: Probably in her early seventies.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well... See if...
[SPEAKER_00]: There must have been quite a difference there if he married her at twenty-three.
[SPEAKER_00]: Twenty-two, I think.
[SPEAKER_04]: We got that on the tape how his first wife died.
[SPEAKER_04]: She looked after the kids and he married her, huh?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Hey, Stanley Kowalewski himself was about 5'9 or so.
[SPEAKER_04]: Spare.
[SPEAKER_04]: He looks much like he looked, I guess, in his pictures as a ball player.
[SPEAKER_04]: Pretty, uh, thinning gray hair.
[SPEAKER_04]: Friendly.
[SPEAKER_04]: Smile.
[SPEAKER_04]: White on the back of his mouth.
[SPEAKER_04]: What was he wearing?
[SPEAKER_00]: A pair of gray pants.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pedro slippers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Brown wool socks.
[SPEAKER_00]: Long underwear.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you see that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, flannel shirt.
[SPEAKER_00]: We won't have your word on it, Jacob.